"lang"
{
	"Language" "Spanish"
	"Tokens"
	{
		// BreakinBenny: Soundscripts only display these when (maxplayers == 1),
		// otherwise the game will only show captions for choreographed scenes.
		
		"training.intro"						"Welcome to the Fortress Forever Training! Over the course of this level, you will learn techniques that will come in handy on the battlefield. Head through the door in front of you to get started."
		"training.all_complete"					"You have completed the Fortress Forever Training. Now, get on the battlefield and show everyone what you're capable of!"
			
		"training.v_conc01"						"You have been switched to Scout, and are now going to learn to concussion jump! To perform one, throw a concussion grenade on the ground, stand on top of it, and jump before it explodes. To go as far as possible, be at the peak of your jump when the grenade explodes. Try to jump to the lasers!"
		"training.v_conc02"						"To achieve maximum vertical height, be at the peak of your jump when the grenade explodes."
		"training.v_conc_timeout"				"Throw a concussion grenade on the ground, stand on top of it, and jump before it explodes. To go as far as possible, be at the peak of your jump when the grenade explodes. Try to jump to the lasers."
			
		"training.a_conc01"						"Now throw a concussion grenade on the ground, stand a few feet in front of it, and jump just before it explodes. The edge of the explosion will give you the biggest boost."
		"training.a_conc02"						"The farther you are from the concussion grenade when it explodes, the farther you will go. But you must stay inside the explosion radius."
		"training.a_conc_timeout"				"Throw a concussion grenade on the ground and stand a few feet in front of it. Jump just before it explodes, and the edge of the explosion will give you the biggest boost."
			
		"training.m_waterconc_start"			"You are now going to learn concussion-jumping out of water. Get in the water."
		"training.m_waterconc01"				"Now throw a concussion grenade on the target, and swim to the top of the water where the arrow is pointing. Hold jump, stay at the top of the water, and wait for the concussion grenade to explode."
		"training.m_waterconc02"				"Remember to position yourself so that you are in front of the concussion grenade."
		"training.m_waterconc_timeout"			"Throw a concussion grenade on the target, and swim to the top of the water where the arrow is pointing. Hold jump to stay at the top of the water, and wait for the concussion grenade to explode."
			
		"training.v_hhconc01"					"You are now going to learn hand-held concussion jumps! Prime a concussion grenade, and hold onto it until it explodes: right before that, jump to get a large boost. Try to jump to the lasers."
		"training.v_hhconc02"					"Jump right when the concussion grenade explodes."
		"training.v_hhconc_timeout"				"Prime a concussion grenade, and hold onto it until it explodes: right before it does, jump to get a large boost."
			
		"training.a_hhconc01"					"Now, hand-held concussion jump to get across that gap. Prime a concussion grenade, and then run forwards and jump as the concussion grenade is about to explode. The earlier you jump, the less vertical height you get."
		"training.a_hhconc02"					"Prime a concussion grenade, run forwards, and jump as the grenade explodes."
		"training.a_hhconc_timeout"				"Prime a concussion grenade, run forwards and jump as the concussion grenade explodes."
			
		"training.v_rj01"						"You've been switched to Soldier, and are now going to learn rocketjumping. Rocketjump by firing at the ground, and jumping right after you shoot. Try to reach the lasers!"
		"training.v_rj02"						"To achieve maximal vertical height while rocketjumping, look straight down and jump as close to when you shoot as you can."
		"training.v_rj_timeout"					"Look down, shoot a rocket, and jump right after you shoot. The closer you time your jump to the rocket's impact, the higher you will go."
			
		"training.a_rj01"						"Now, rocketjump to get across the gap. Run towards the gap, fire a rocket near your feet, and jump. The explosion should carry you across."
		"training.a_rj02"						"Run backwards, shoot a rocket, and jump so that the rocket explodes on the ground near you."
		"training.a_rj_timeout"					"Run towards the gap, fire a rocket near your feet, and jump. The explosion should carry you across."
			
		"training.v_pipe01"						"You've been switched to Demoman, and are now going to learn pipejumping. Pipejump by shooting two pipebombs next to each other, stand on top of them, then detonate them and jump at the same time. Try to reach the lasers!"
		"training.v_pipe02"						"Remember to put the pipe-grenades as close together as possible, and to stand directly on top of them to achieve the maximum vertical boost. Then jump right as you detonate the pipes."
		"training.v_pipe_timeout"				"Shooting two pipebombs next to each other, and stand on top of them: detonate the pipes and jump at the same time."
			
		"training.a_pipe01"						"Now only use one pipe-grenade. Start from behind the pipe and run forward, then jump and detonate the pipe when you get in front of it. Try to jump across the gap."
		"training.a_pipe02"						"Run from behind to the pipe-grenade, then jump and detonate the pipe when you get in front of it."
		"training.a_pipe_timeout"				"Shoot one pipe-grenade, start from behind it and run forward, then jump and detonate the pipe when you get in front of it. Try to jump across the gap."
			
		"training.a_ft01"						"You have been switched to Pyro, and are now going to learn using the jetpack! Use your secondary attack while in the air to activate it. Run forwards, jump and use the jetpack to cross the gap."
		"training.a_ft02"						"Jump and use the jetpack to get across the gap."
		"training.a_ft_timeout"					"The Pyro's special ability is a jetpack. Run forwards, jump, and use your jetpack to cross the gap."
			
		"training.move_doublejump01"			"It's time for movement techniques! The first one you'll learn is the double-jump, which is performed by chaining two jumps together in quick succession, giving you a boost in height.<delay:11.3>This is most often done by jumping up an upwards ramp twice. If you hold the JUMP key, you will jump as soon as you touch the ground.<delay:20>Use the platform in front of you to do a double-jump up to the ledge!"
		"training.move_doublejump02"			"Run towards the ledge and jump onto the platform. Keep holding your JUMP key to do a double-jump!"
		"training.move_doublejump_timeout"		"A double-jump is performed by chaining two jumps together in quick succession, giving you a boost in height. This is most often done by jumping up an upwards ramp twice.<delay:9.7>If you hold the JUMP key, you will jump as soon as you touch the ground. Use the platform in front of you to do a double-jump up to the ledge!"
			
		"training.move_aircontrol_start"		"Air-control is a fundamental movement technique used to change your trajectory, while in the air. To do it, Mouselook smoothly in the direction you want to go while simultaneously strafing that way.<delay:12.8>If you Mouselook too fast, you lose speed!<delay:15.8>Also, do not press forwards while air-controlling, as it'll limit your ability to do so!"
		"training.move_aircontrol02"			"To turn while in the air, strafe either left or right and at the same time smoothly Mouselook in that direction."
		"training.move_aircontrol_timeout"		"Air-control by Mouselooking smoothly in the direction you want to go, while strafing in the same direction.<delay:6.75>If you Mouselook too fast, you lose speed. Don't press forwards while air-controlling either, as that will limit your air-controlling ability!"
			
		"training.move_aircontrolpush01"		"Now air-control to your left to get across the pit. The arrows on the ground will give you a boost!"
		"training.move_aircontrolpush02"		"Strafe to the left, and at the same time turn that way."
		"training.move_aircontrolpush_timeout"	"Air-control to your left to cross the pit, the arrows on the ground will give you a boost."
		
		"training.move_aircontrolspeed_start"	"Air-controlling can also be used to gain speed. Mouselooking smoothly while strafing in the air will increase your speed over time, air-control around this circle and try to get to 700 speed!"
		"training.move_aircontrolspeed02"		"Mouselook <I>smoothly<I> in the same direction you are strafing in to gain speed."
		"training.move_aircontrolspeed_timeout"	"Air-controlling can also be used to gain speed. Mouselooking smoothly while strafing in the air will increase your speed over time, air-control around this circle and try to get up to 700 speed."
		
		"training.move_aircontrolbhop_start"	"Now try using air-control to switch directions. Avoid the sharp corners, and try to get across the gap."
		"training.move_aircontrolbhop02"		"Stop strafing in one direction, then strafe in the other to change directions."
		"training.move_aircontrolbhop_timeout"	"Keep strafing in different directions while air-controlling to get across the gap. Avoid sharp corners!"
		
		"training.move_bhop1_start"				"Bunnyhopping is a technique to gain speed using both jumps and air-controlling. Cross the gap by jumping on each stepping stone!<delay:8>During each jump, air-control to speed up, and hold your JUMP button to avoid slowing down when you touch the ground.<delay:16.3>The game is slowed to half-speed for this section!"
		"training.move_bhop2_start"				"The speed has been increased a little bit, it is now at 75% normal speed for this section!"
		"training.move_bhop3_start"				"Now the game is back at <B>full<B> speed. Go for it!"
		"training.move_bhop02"					"Make sure to hold your JUMP button in order to maintain your speed each time you land. Remember to Mouselook smoothly to gain speed in the air!"
		"training.move_bhop_timeout"			"Cross the gap by jumping on each stepping stone. During each jump, air-control to gain speed!<delay:6.8>Hold your JUMP button to avoid slowing down when you touch the ground."
		
		"training.move_rampslide_start"			"While moving fast, you can slide up a sloped surface, this technique is called rampsliding. Rampslide up the ramp in front of you, air-control to your left, and then continue rampsliding up the second ramp.<delay:15>The arrows on the ground will give you a boost."
		"training.move_rampslide02"				"You don't need to jump or press forwards while rampsliding. At the top of the first ramp, air-control to avoid losing speed."
		"training.move_rampslide_timeout"		"While moving fast, you can slide up a sloped surface, this technique is called rampsliding. Rampslide up the ramp in front of you, air-control to your left, and then continue rampsliding up the second ramp.<delay:14.7>The arrows on the ground will give you a boost."
		
		"training.move_trimp_start"				"While rampsliding, you can jump to <B>trimp<B>. Trimping converts your horizontal speed into a vertical one, giving you a high boost.<delay:10>Rampslide and then trimp to get to the ledge!"
		"training.move_trimp02"					"Time your jump so that you land on the ledge."
		"training.move_trimp_timeout"			"While rampsliding, you can jump to <B>trimp<B>. Trimping converts your horizontal speed into a vertical one, giving you a high boost.<delay:8.5>Rampslide and then trimp to get to the ledge!"
		
		"training.all_scout_start"				"Well done on getting this far! Now grab the flag at the other end of the arena, and bring it back to the capture point as fast as possible. Concussion-jumps, rampslides, double-jumps, trimping, and air-control will all help tremendously!<delay:15>Capture the flag within 25 seconds to complete the stage and get a bronze medal. Do it under 20 seconds to get a silver medal, and under 15 to get a gold medal!"
		"training.all_scout_bronze"				"Congratulations! You've received a <clr:205,127,50>bronze medal<clr:255,255,255>."
		"training.all_scout_silver"				"Congratulations! You've received a <clr:192,192,192>silver medal<clr:255,255,255>. You sure know your stuff!"
		"training.all_scout_gold"				"Congratulations! You've received a <clr:255,215,0>gold medal<clr:255,255,255>! YOU'RE A REAL PRO!"
		
		"testcommands"							"<clr:255,0,0>This is red<I> and italics<B> and<cr>bold<B><I><clr:255,255,255> white again.
	}
}